Remember...
牢記
I just turned 65.
我剛滿65歲
I made a wish on my birthday.
我在生日那天許下一個願望
Just like a child would...
像孩子一樣
Another impossible wish, of course.
當然，那是一個不可能實現的願望
You know what I wished for?
你知道我許了什麼願嗎？
To be a good man.
我想做好人
You know me.
你了解我
I do.
是的
You're a good man.
你是個好人
KILL
殺
Nesrin, pulling a gun is so different than to pulling the trigger.
內斯林，用槍指著人和開槍是兩碼事
You couldn't find any of this footage on the internet or on TV.
你不能在網際網路或電視上找到任何這樣的素材
Welcome to the fan club of the first real Turkish serial killer.
歡迎來到首個真正的土耳其連環殺手的粉絲俱樂部
Do whatever it takes, but stop them.
盡一切努力阻止他們
Tufan Elibol, whom the killer used to throw us off his track
圖凡·埃裏博爾，兇手曾把我們從對他的追蹤中甩掉
will be instrumental in catching him.
將有助於我們抓住他
The killer will be a victim to his own game.
兇手將成為自己遊戲的受害者
Go on, get out.
出去吧
Clouds foaming overhead.
我的頭是泡沫狀的雲
The sea within, the sea without.
我的內外都是大海
I'm a walnut tree in Gülhane Park.
我是古爾哈內公園的一棵核桃樹
Neither you realize this...
你不知道
Nor the police.
警察也不知道
I MET A GIRL TODAY HER NAME IS NEVRA ELMAS
我今天遇到了一個女孩，她的名字叫做內芙拉·艾爾瑪斯
I TRUST ONLY HER BECAUSE NEVRA GETS ME
我隻相信她，因為內芙拉懂我
IT IS NEVRA'S BIRTHDAY TODAY I GOT HER A PRESENT
今天是內芙拉的生日，我給她準備了一個禮物
NEVRA AND I HAVE A SECRET
內芙拉和我有一個秘密
I TOLD NEVRA EVERYTHING BUT SHE WON'T BELIEVE ME
我把一切都告訴了內芙拉，但她不相信我
TONIGHT, A STAR FELL FROM THE SKY
今夜，一顆流星從天而降
I MADE A WISH
我許了一個願
I WISHED THAT THEY ALL DIE
我希望他們都死了
- They're all dead. - All?
-他們都死了  -全死了？
Ufuk had two brothers.
烏福克有兩個兄弟
One of them was shot at his workplace. The other one in the forest.
其中一個在他的工作地點被槍殺  另一個死在森林裏
Our guy?
是我們的案子嗎？
- Messages on both their foreheads. - Their father's outside.
-額頭上有消息  -他們的父親在外麵
Came to pick them up, waiting on paperwork.
把他們接過來，等著做文書工作
He can't. We need to do an autopsy.
不行  我們需要做驗屍
I couldn't tell him. I could never tell him.
我不能告訴他   我不能告訴他
Come on! Come on!
好啦好啦！
I'll tell him.
我去告訴他
Son!
兒子！
You killed them!
是你殺了他們！
- You killed my children! - Salih...
-你殺了我的孩子們！-薩利赫
- Salih, please don't. - You killed my babies!
-薩利赫，別這樣  -你殺了我的孩子們！
You ended them! You ended my babies.
你殺死了他們！你殺了我的孩子們
Are you happy now? Are you happy now, Nevra?
內芙拉  你現在高興了嗎？
- Did you get what you wanted? - Shut up!
-得到了想要的東西嗎  -閉嘴
If you had been looking for the killer instead of going after Ufuk.
如果你一直在尋找殺手，而不是去追捕烏福克
- They both would be alive now. - Shut up!
-他們倆現在一定都還活著  -閉嘴！
Tell me I'm lying!
告訴我我在撒謊！
Damn!
該死的！
I want to die!
讓我死了吧！
What happened to me?
我發生什麼事了？
We had to pump your stomach, Zuhal.
祖哈爾，我們得給你洗胃
Why?
為什麼？
What happened?
發生了什麼？
You had alcohol poisoning when you arrived.
你酒精中毒了
Nevra?
內芙拉？
Nevra, what are you doing?
內芙拉，你在做什麼？
It's fine. I had a nosebleed. I got blood on my sleeve.
冇事  我流鼻血了  袖子上沾了血
- Are you alright, daughter? - I'm not.
-你還好嗎，女兒？-我不好
I'm not alright at all.
我一點都不好
You are sad about Ufuk, right? Poor boy.
你為烏福感到難過吧？可憐的男孩
I'm powerless.
我無能為力
People are dying around me, and I'm powerless!
我身邊的人在一個個死掉，而我卻無能為力！
It's driving me mad!
我快要發瘋了！
I try to control myself.
我試圖控製自己
I tense every muscle in my body just so nobody suspects anything.
我繃緊體內的所有肌肉，所以冇人懷疑
Suspect what?
懷疑什麼
That I'm afraid. That I'm afraid. I'm so afraid.
懷疑我害怕，我真的很害怕
I'm afraid that I'm never going to catch the killer!
害怕我永遠也抓不到殺手！
I'm so afraid!
我好害怕！
I'm so afraid...
我好怕
Nevra, my darling...
內芙拉，親愛的
It was so hard, not crying in front of the crowd.
在人群麵前保持不哭，這太難受了。
I ran and I ran, and here I am.
我跑開了  來到這裏
My darling... Just like when you were a child.
我的寶貝  你還像小時候一樣
You'd run home, about to piss your pants.
快要尿褲子時跑回家裏
You'd barely make it.
勉強憋住
Are you feeling better?
你感覺好些了嗎？
Yes. I think.
是的，我覺得好些了
- Don't be afraid, Nevra. - Mom...
-別害怕，內芙拉  -媽媽
Hush.
安靜
Don't be afraid.
不要害怕
Don't be afraid to be afraid.
不要因為害怕而感到害怕
Plus... So what?
害怕又能怎樣？
I'm afraid, as well.
我也很害怕
You're never afraid.
不要怕
That was then.
已經過去了
I'm so scared that something will to happen to you.
我好怕你會發生什麼事
Come on, I'll wash it.
給我洗吧
And...
另外……
They can't even get a bloodstain out...
他們甚至都不會沾上血跡
Yet they go become cops.
但他們可以成為警察
Some cop you are.
你是個真警察
- Someone sent you flowers, Zuhal. - Who?
-有人給你送花了，祖哈爾-誰？
- Me. - You can leave when you're feeling better.
-我  -感覺好一些了就可以出院
- You didn't go? - No.
-你冇走嗎？-冇
You were here through the night?
你整夜都在這裏嗎？
Hello?
餵？
Yes, I'm here.
對，我在這
I have the file.
文件在我這
Where are you?
你在哪？
Hello?
餵？
Hello? You're breaking up. Hello?
餵？信號不好  餵？
Cemil, I'm so sorry.
塞米爾，我很抱歉
I'm so embarrassed. I don't know what to say.
我好尷尬  不知道該說些什麼
I can't even imagine the spot I put you in.
我甚至無法想象我把你放在了什麼位置
I should quit the job.
我應該辭職
What am I to do, Cemil?
我該怎麼辦，塞米爾？
WATER IT TWICE A WEEK
每周澆水兩次
Water it twice a week...
And come with me. Let's go.
跟我一起走吧
- What will you do now? - Get back to Istanbul.
-你現在要做什麼？-回到伊斯坦佈爾
I need to ask you something.
我要問你一件事
Why did you lie, Selim and you?
你為什麼撒謊，塞利姆和你？
About how the house burned down.
關於房子如何被燒毀的
Why would I lie?
我為什麼要撒謊？
I already told you.
我已經跟你說過
Selim forgets to take his pills and hallucinates.
塞利姆忘了吃藥 産生了幻想
- That's all. - Fine. If you say so.
-就是這樣  -好吧，如果你這樣說的話
Why wouldn't I tell you if I knew something?
如果我知道什麼，我為什麼不告訴你？
There's something that scares you. I'd forgotten about it.
有一些會讓你害怕的事情我都已經忘記了
What's that?
什麼事？
You're scared of being left alone. You always were.
你總是害怕一個人呆著
What would you do if something were to happen to Selim?
如果塞利姆發生什麼事情，你會怎麼做？
If you knew that I was scared of being left alone,
如果你知道我害怕一個人呆著，
why did you up and leave?
那你為什麼離開？
You didn't take me to Istanbul.
你冇帶我去伊斯坦佈爾
You were being scared of loneliness, and I was scared of you.
你怕寂寞，而我怕你
Fine! Then don't come here with tears in your eyes ever again.
好！那就別再流眼淚了
Why shouldn't I? Didn't you tell me not to be afraid of being afraid?
為什麼不呢？你不是告訴我不要害怕嗎？
Take care.
照顧好自己
Hello?
餵？
You're breaking up. I can't hear you.
信號不好，我聽不到你說話
Hello?
餵？
The door is opening.
門開了
Stop! Stop!
站住！別動！
Call the police! Call the police, Galip!
報警！加利普！報警！
- Are you alright? - Take your gun.
-你還好嗎？-拿槍
Are you alright?
你還好嗎？
- What happened? Did they find him? - I just got word.
-發生了什麼？他們找到他了嗎？-我剛得到消息
He's trapped in a shopping centre's garage.
他被睏在購物中心的車庫裏
Yes. We have all the exits blocked.
是的，我們已將所有出口都被封鎖了
This is the only exit. He's definitely in here.
這是唯一的出口  他肯定在這裏
Let's go!
我們走吧！
I found his costume. He's going up to the roof!
我發現了他的服裝  他上屋頂了！
To be honest...
老實說
I don't even like the taste of alcohol, Cemil.
我甚至不喜歡酒精的味道，塞米爾
But after I have that first glass...
但是當我喝了第一杯之後
Something happens...
有些事情發生了
I can't stop myself.
我無法阻止自己
All I want to do is drink.
我隻想喝酒
No matter what.
無論如何都要喝
Come what may.
不管發生什麼
"All I need right now is a drink. Just let me have one more drink."
“我現在隻需要喝一杯，隻要再喝一杯”
I can't stop myself.
我無法阻止自己
There this writer called Bukowski, you might've heard of him.
有一位作家叫佈科夫斯基，你可能聽說過他
You know what he said?
你知道他說什麼嗎？
He said drinking is a form of suicide.
他說喝酒是自殺的一種形式
He said drinking yourself unconscious is attempted suicide.
他說喝酒使自己昏迷那是企圖自殺
- I don't want to die, Cemil. - Are you sure?
-我不想死，塞米爾  -你確定嗎？
Of course I am. I don't even want to talk about this.
當然  我甚至一點都不想談論這個
Talking about this with you is such an embarrassment for me.
和你談論這個對我來說很尷尬
Hurting someone else is embarrassing, Zuhal.
傷害別人才令人尷尬，祖哈爾
There's nothing embarrassing about having hurt yourself.
傷害自己冇有什麼尷尬的
You have enough problems as it is.
你的問題已經夠多了
- Would you like to leave? - No.
-你要離開嗎？-不
- We should stay. - Alright.
-我們應該留下來  -好
I should tell you why we're here, then.
我應該告訴你為什麼我們在這裏
There was this elder in Kambura. Turan.
坎佈拉有一位名叫圖蘭的長者
He took me aside one day and told me I wasn't the first.
他有一天把我帶到一邊，告訴我我不是第一個
I asked him what he meant.
我問他是什麼意思
"You're not the first boy whose education the Kamburan people paid for.
“你不是第一個由坎佈蘭人支付學費的男孩
"They paid for three more children before you." he said.
他說：“他們在你之前還付了三個孩子的學費。”
I was surprised.
我很驚訝
I asked him where they were, what they did now.
我問他這些人在哪裏，他們現在做什麼
They paid for the first one's education. He said he was a good student.
他們付了第一人的學費。他說他是一個好學生。
Finished college. Started a business. Made a lot of money.
大學畢業後開辦企業賺了很多錢
But he forgot about Kambura.
但是他忘記了坎佈拉
He never went back to Kambura.
他再也冇有回來過
He said they sometimes saw him on TV, but changed the channel immediately.
他說有時他們會在電視上看到他，但馬上就換頻道
There was a second boy. They paid for his education, as well.
人們為第二個男孩也交了學費
"He finished college,
“他讀完大學，
and we sent him to London for a graduate degree."
然後人們把他送到倫敦攻讀研究生學位”
But he became a gambler.
但是他卻成了賭徒
All that money that the Kamburans scraped together...
坎佈拉人給他湊得所有錢
He lost it all on roulette.
他在賭桌上全輸光了
Apparently, he was jailed at some point.
顯然，他進了監獄
After that, no one saw him
在那之後，冇有人看到他
or heard of him ever again.
也冇人再聽到過他的消息
Their one last hope...
他們最後的希望……
They paid for one last boy's education.
他們付了最後一個男孩的學費
He got into medical school.
他進了醫學院
But he started drinking.
但是他開始喝酒
I met him, actually.
我遇見了他
Rahim was his name.
他的名字是拉希姆
Five-six years older than I was.
比我大五六歲
I went up to him...
我去找他
"Rahim,
“拉希姆，
a whole village depends on you."
整個村莊都取決於你”
"You'll become a doctor
“你會成為一名醫生
and cure the people who raised you."
並治愈那些曾養育你的人”
You know what he said to me?
你知道他對我說什麼嗎？
He told me they never asked him if he wanted an education.
他告訴我，他們從未問過他是否想要接受教育
Told me they should educate themselves.
告訴我他們應該自學
It was right here that I had that conversation
我們就在這裏進行了交談
with Rahim, Zuhal.
和拉希姆交談，祖哈爾
He was an intern at this hospital.
他是這家醫院的實習生
He came down here to drink in secret.
他來這兒偷偷的喝酒
Now...
現在
I'll tell you why we're here.
我告訴你為什麼我們在這裏
You're going to make a decision.
你要做出決定
I never saw Rahim's face again.
我再也冇有見過拉希姆的臉
Will I get to see yours?
我還能見到你的臉嗎？
My father never asked me, either, Cemil.
我父親也從未問過我，塞米爾
He never asked me anything.
他從冇問過我任何事
Never asked me if I wanted to go to boarding school.
從來冇有問過我是否要去寄宿學校
If I wanted to go to college...
是否想上大學
He was always so distant.
他總是離我很遙遠
I told him I was moving to Australia.
我告訴他我要去澳洲
"Farewell," he said.
“永別了，”他說
I was so lonely.
我好寂寞
I sometimes look at my photos from those days.
有時候我看著老照片
I'm always by myself.
我總是一個人
In the photos,
在照片中
there are beautiful landscapes.
有美麗的風景
Beautiful bridges...
美麗的橋梁
Statues...
塑像
And me...
還有我
Just me...
隻有我
You know what I'd actually like?
你知道我到底想要什麼嗎？
I want the photos...
我想要照片……
I want the photos to have my mom in them.
我希望照片中有媽媽
I want my mom, my dad and I together.
我想要我媽媽，爸爸和我在一起
I want nothing else in the photos.
其他什麼都不要
I want nothing else.
什麼都不要了
Even if we're in front of the best view,
即使我們站在最好的風景前
in the most beautiful place in the world,
在世界上最美麗的地方
I want all of it gone. I want us and only us to remain.
我希望那一切都消失掉，隻留下我們
Because...
因為……
We'd be enough for each other.
我們有彼此就足夠了
But it didn't turn out that way.
但事實並非如此
I'd remember.
我記得
Even if there were nothing else in the photos,
即使照片冇有其他內容
I'd look at my mom and dad's faces,
我看著爸爸媽媽的臉
and I'd know that
我知道
we were standing in front of a huge waterfall.
我們站在一個巨大的瀑佈前
I know it's not in the photo,
我知道那不在照片裏
but we're standing by a huge sycamore tree.
而是我們站在一棵巨大的梧桐樹旁
That would be enough for me. But...
這對我來說就足夠了
But it was never like that. Never.
但是從來冇有那樣
The photos have only me in them.
這些照片隻有我一個人
And the setting sun.
和落日
The setting sun.
落日
The sun.
太陽
There it is, always.
太陽總是在那裏
But it's setting.
但這是背景
I...
我……
I've never been able to forgive my father, Cemil.
我從來冇能原諒我的父親  塞米爾
- He must've had a reason. - I wish he'd shared it with me.
-他一定有原因  -我希望他能和我分享
- Let's go, Cemil. Let's get out of here? - Sure. Let's go. However...
-走吧，塞米爾，我們離開這裏吧？ -當然，走吧
I need you to make me a promise.
我需要你嚮我保證
- I promise never to drink again. - No. It's not that.
-我保證永遠不會再喝酒  - 不，不是
It's something else.
還有別的
Promise me you'll never forget this place. And this smell.
答應我，你永遠不會忘記這個地方和這個氣味
I do. I promise. I'll never forget it.
我保證  我永遠不會忘記
Your father looked after me. It's my turn to look after you now.
你父親曾照顧我  現在輪到我照顧你
That's nonsense.
說什麼傻話
My job is to look after you.
我的工作是照顧你
- That's nonsense. - No.
-別這樣說  -不
That's different.
那不一樣
Answer me this one question.
回答我這個問題
Is there room for me in that photo?
照片裏有我的位置嗎？
Cemil?
塞米爾？
We're done here.
我們結束了
- Are you alright? Are you cold? - I'm fine. A bit cold, maybe.
-你還好嗎？冷嗎？-我很好，也許有點冷
- Don't worry. You'll get over it. - Thank you so much.
-別擔心，你會克服的  -非常感謝
There's this writer.
曾經有一位作家
Named Coubert...
名叫庫伯
He said that...
他說過
Love is the only adventure left on this earth.
愛是地球上唯一的冒險
That's what he says.
他就是這麼說的
I see.
我懂了
MORGUE
停屍房
This is a joke, right?
開玩笑的吧？
There's only one entrance and one exit to the garage.
車庫隻有一個入口和一個出口
But there's no one inside...
但是裏麵冇有人
With your permission,
在你的許可之下，
I'd like to take this to the lab for DNA analysis.
我想帶它去實驗室進行DNA分析
Sure, take it.
當然可以
Is Nevra around?
內芙拉在嗎？
Yeah. She's here.
是的，她在這裏
I want to ask you something.
我想問你點事兒
Do you know what's the most dangerous thing for a murder specialist?
你知道對一個謀殺專家來說最危險的是什麼嗎?
Obsession.
癡迷
You get an idea.
你有個主意
Then you start believing it. It takes hold in your mind.
然後你就開始相信它了
Then it turns into an obsession. It blinds you.
然後變成迷戀  它蒙蔽你的雙眼
You can always have theories, of course.
當然，你總是可以有理論的
But do you know the difference between a theory and a conspiracy?
但是你知道理論和陰謀之間的區別嗎？
I'll tell you that, as well.
我也可以告訴你
Theories are smart.
理論很明智
Conspiracy theories are sicknesses.
陰謀論是疾病
Because the evidence for a theory is rooted in truth.
因為一個理論的證據是基於真理的
But the evidence for a conspiracy is another conspiracy theory.
但是陰謀的證據是另一種陰謀論
Itself, in other words.
換句話說，陰謀本身
It's right even when it's wrong.
即使錯了也是對的
A conspiracy theory is never wrong.
陰謀論永遠不會錯
You know who else is never wrong?
你知道還有誰永遠不會錯嗎？
Dumb people.
愚蠢的人
Don't get me wrong. I'm not only talking about you, talking about myself, as well.
不要誤會我的意思，我不僅是在說你，也在說我自己
That's why we're going to build a perimeter of logic together.
這就是為什麼我們要一起構建邏輯邊界
We'll keep running into each other. Until we find the truth.
我們會經常碰麵  直到我們找到真相
We will consider every single possibility.
我們將會考慮到每一個可能性
Even the possibility that none of this has anything to do with Kambura.
甚至是與坎佈拉無關的可能性
- Who is it? - He didn't have an ID on him.
-是誰？-他身上冇有身份證
I didn't talk to him. I waited for you to arrive, Cemil.
我冇有和他說話  等著你來，塞米爾
Good. Let's find out what's his problem with Kambura.
好，我們來看看他與坎佈拉的關係到底是什麼
By the way...
順便說說
You should be glad that Ufuk handled himself.
你應該很高興烏福克自殺了
Yes, Cemil. We couldn't stop him, sadly.
是的，塞米爾   可悲的是我們無法阻止他
You made up for it, though.
你將功補過了
- Sir, his connection to the victim... - Nevra...
-長官，他與受害人的關係……  -內芙拉
- Are you talking about the house? - Yes.
-你在說房子嗎？-是的
Nevra, we went there. You read the report.
內芙拉，我們去過那裏  你也看過了報告
Nobody burned it.
冇人縱火
I don't believe that report.
我不相信那個報告
- Is that so? - Yes.
-是嗎 -是的
On what grounds? Your mom's husband? What was his name?
基於什麼理由？你媽媽的丈夫嗎？ 他叫什麼名字？
Selim.
塞利姆
What about what Ufuk told us? His brothers were killed.
烏福克告訴我們的事呢？他的兄弟被殺了
You went there to interrogate Ufuk and utter chaos took over.
你去那裏審問烏福，結果引發了徹底的混亂
I got calls from the ministry asking what's going on in Kambura.
我接到了政府部門的電話，並詢問了坎佈拉的情況
I swear I don't know anything about Kambura.
我發誓我對坎佈拉一無所知
I don't even know where it is!
我甚至不知道它在哪裏！
I swear I'm not him!
我發誓我不是兇手！
Please don't!
不要！
Speak! Why did you kill all those people? Speak!
說話！你為什麼殺死這些人？說話！
But sir, we also know that
但是先生，我們也了解到
the deceased Naz ??rtük is also connected to Kambura.
死者納茲·切爾基斯也與坎佈拉有聯係
- She worked in the municipality office. - Sure, but when?
-她曾在市政廳工作  -當然，但是什麼時候？
Twenty years ago? Forty years ago? When?
二十年前？四十年前？什麼時候？
- Please don't! Please don't! - Tell me who you are.
-請不要！請不要！-告訴我你是誰
What did you want from those people? Why did you shoot that women? Why?
你想從那些人那裏得到什麼？為什麼要殺掉那個女人？為什麼？
They'll kill me! They'll put me in the ground!
他們會殺了我的！
I'm the one who'll put you in the ground!
我是才是會殺掉你的人！
I'll bury you so deep that no one will see you ever again.
我會把你埋得很深，以至冇有人能發現你
Alright! How about this?
好吧，那這樣呢？
I got a call from narcotics today.
我今天接到緝毒局的電話
The woman who was killed in the parking garage, you know who she is?
在停車場被殺的那個女人，你知道她是誰嗎？
I know that she worked at a logistics firm as an accountant.
我知道她在阿塔物流公司當過會計
Not even close. There's no such logistics firm.
不是，根本冇有合格物流公司
It's a front. They were running drugs, Nevra.
他們在販毒，內芙拉
Narcotics has been after them for six months.
緝毒局已經追蹤了他們六個月
They convince the woman to turn state's evidence.
他們說服那個女人轉為證人
They were supposed to meet today.
他們本該在今天見麵
She went to the office to gather evidence.
她去事務室收集證據
But she's gone. So is the evidence.
但是她死了  所以那些證據冇有了
Now. Do you still think...
現在  你還覺得
That the murders are connected to Kambura?
謀殺案與坎佈拉有關嗎？
I saw it in the papers.
我在報紙上看到了
A guy in a cat costume was killing people after people!
一個穿著貓服裝的人正在殺人！
The people I told you about gave me the hit on the accountant woman.
我說的那些人給了我那女人的情報
I just got out of prison.
我剛出獄
I couldn't go back in. But I needed the money!
我不能回去坐牢  但是我需要錢！
So I donned the cat costume. I thought it would be a good idea.
所以我穿了貓服裝，我認為那是個好主意
He's killed four, five, so many people!
他殺了四個，五個，這麼多人！
I thought I could pin it on him.
我以為可以算在他頭上
I thought it would be forgotten. What will you do to me?
我以為我做的事不會有人知道  你會對我做什麼？
Please!
來吧！
動手吧！
Why aren't you saying anything? Please!
你怎麼不說話
Tell me how much you were paid, you bastard. Tell me!
告訴我你收了多少錢，混蛋  快告訴我！
If all that isn't convincing enough, here's the file on that Terazi guy.
如果這還不足以令人信服，這是那個泰拉齊的檔案
Read his file.
閱讀他的檔案
What does it say?
上麵寫的什麼
Go ahead. Read it out loud.
繼續大聲朗讀
- Post-traumatic stress disorder. - That's right!
-創傷後應激障礙  -是的！
He was sick!
他病了！
But what did I do?
但是我做了什麼？
I asked myself, "What if Nevra's right?"
我問自己：“內芙拉說得對嗎？”
What if they burned that house down? What if that report was fake?
如果是他們把那所房子燒毀了怎麼辦？如果那個報告是假的怎麼辦？
Then what happened today?
然後現在發生了什麼？
We found out that the woman who was killed had nothing to do with Kambura.
我們發現被殺的那個女人與坎佈拉毫無聯係
What did I do? I accepted that.
我是怎樣做的？  我接受了
Now, Nevra, I'm begging you... It's your turn to accept it.
現在，內芙拉，我求你了……該你接受事實了
If you want to look for connections between the victims, look elsewhere!
如果要在受害者之間尋找聯係，找找其他方嚮吧！
Forget about that burnt down house!
忘了那座被燒毀的房子！
Listen, Nevra.
聽著，內華拉
Sometimes things don't turn out the way we expect them to.
有時候事情並冇有像我們期望的那樣發生
We want them to be another way. We imagine them to be. But they're not.
我們希望它是另一種方式。我們以為它是。但並不是
They're nothing but illusions.
不過是幻想罷了
Get out.
出去吧
Then we get a phone call, and wake up.
然後我們接到一個電話，醒了過來
Sir? Can I have that file?
先生，我可以拿那個文件嗎？
I wasted my breath, didn't I?
我都白說了，不是嗎？
You'll do what you want anyway.
無論如何你都會做你想做的
Sure. Take it.
當然可以
Do what you want.
做你想做的
I'm so glad we finally got to meet.
我很高興我們終於見麵了
I've been telling him.
我一直在告訴他
If you hadn't come to me, I'd have come to you.
如果你冇有來找我，我會去找你的
I was almost about to, in fact. I even have your address!
實際上我正準備去了  我甚至有你的地址！
As you might guess,
你要知道
communication with patients' families is a must for us.
與患者家人溝通對我們來說是很重要的
Especially when it comes to patients like your father.
尤其是像你父親這樣的病人
It's very important that the people close to them
與他們親近的人非常重要
get together to support them.
聚在一起支援他們
- Again, welcome, Zuhal. - Thank you.
-再次歡迎你，祖哈爾  -謝謝
I have some questions prepared.
我準備了一些問題
Let's move to the table and I can begin asking them.
來辦公桌這邊，我來問問題
I hope you've been doing your homework.
我希望你有在做功課
Agah, I don't know why I said yes to this!
阿加，我不知道我為什麼同意了這件事
This is madness! I have to tell your doctor the truth.
這太瘋狂了！我必須告訴醫生真相
What will you tell him? Don't be silly.
你會告訴他什麼？別傻了
- I can tell him it was all a joke. - You can't do that. It's too late.
-我可以告訴他，這隻是個玩笑  -你不能了，為時已晚
I'll tell him the truth, then.
那我告訴他真相
I'll tell him Agah's daughter is undergoing cancer treatment.
我可以告訴他阿加的女兒正在接受癌癥治療
He thinks telling her will upset her.
他認為告訴她會讓她不高興
He was worried that you might want to visit his home, so we came up with this.
他擔心你可能要去他的家，所以我們想到了這個計畫
Gonca, my girl, please!
貢卡，親愛的，拜托！
If you won't do it for me, do it for Münir.
如果你不願意為我做，那就為尼穆爾做
You've been his veterinarian for years. You practically raised Münir!
你已經擔任它的獸醫很多年了，你幾乎養育了尼穆爾！
Let's forget about that, even. Zuhal is what's important here!
先不說這個  祖哈爾也很重要啊！
What would Zuhal do in her state if she found out her father's sick?
如果祖哈爾發現父親病了，祖哈爾會怎樣？
You're a doctor of many years.
你從醫很多年了
Could you take such a responsibility?
你能承擔這樣的責任嗎？
Don't you know how important optimism is when it comes to cancer treatment?
你不知道在癌癥治療方麵樂觀是多麼重要嗎？
But what next, Agah? How long can we keep it up?
但是接下來，阿加，我們還能維持多久呢？
It's already done. There's nothing to keep up.
已經結束了，後麵也冇什麼事了
He has your number. He might call you once, if that.
他有你的電話  他可能會打給你一次
You'll just nod your head and be done with it.
你隻需點頭就可以了
It was so embarrassing, having to lie. I'm terrible at it.
真是令人尷尬，不得不撒謊，我很害怕
- Do you think he could tell? - Of course not!
-你認為他能看出來嗎？-當然不能！
You were such a great actor! I'm sure he'd never even suspect you.
你真是個好演員！我敢肯定，他絕對不會懷疑你
I'll do whatever you want from me now.
我現在可以做任何你想做的事
I don't want to go through this again.
我不想再經曆這個了
And I hope Zuhal gets her health back.
我希望祖哈爾能恢複健康
Amen. Thank you.
阿門  謝謝你
- I could give you a ride. - It's fine, really.
-我可以載你  -真的不用了
Alright. Alright, then. Thank you so much.
好吧，那麼非常感謝
You were great in there. You deserved an Oscar, I'm telling you.
你在那裏很棒，當之無愧的奧斯卡演員
Ali, I need a phone number.
阿裏，我需要一個電話號碼
Used to work at Kambura Hospital. It's been ten years.
十年前曾在坎佈拉醫院工作的
Psychiatrist Nedim Do?ru.
精神科醫生內地姆·多埃魯
Of course.
好的
Nevra...
內芙拉
The stupid cat costume worked. They found some DNA on it.
那套愚蠢的貓服裝奏效了  他們發現了一些DNA
They're trying to find a match for it.
他們正試圖找到一個匹配的人
If they get a match, this is over.
如果他們得到匹配，那一切就結束了
I need to oversee the autopsy of the triplets.
我要去監督三胞胎的屍檢
You can follow up on the DNA. Good luck.
你可以跟進DNA檢測   祝你好運
To you, as well.
你也是
Thanks.
謝謝
Here we are...
終於……
We're immortalizing this historic moment.
我們使這個曆史性的時刻永生
What are you doing?
你在做什麼？
- Writing my memoir. - Sure you are.
-寫我的回憶錄  -這樣啊
What happens in your memoir? Do you die at the end?
回憶錄中會寫什麼？你最後死了嗎？
Medically, no. But my career? Yes.
從醫學角度來說冇死，但是我的職業生涯死了
- Why? - What do you mean, why?
-為什麼？-什麼為什麼？
Do you know how many corpses come in here every day?
你知道每天有多少具屍體送進來嗎？
Should we call the police or something?
我們應該報警嗎？
I work so much I've forgotten what my place looks like.
我工作太多了，我忘了我的地方看起來像什麼
I'm listening, Timur.
我在聽，帖木兒
Born on the same day,  died on the same day.
同一天出生，同一天死亡
Proper triplets.
真正的三胞胎
That's some investigating!
真是個好調查！
Yes, Nevra?
餵？內芙拉？
Really? I'll be right there.
真的嗎  我馬上過去
- Did they find him? - How did you know?
-他們找到他了嗎？-你怎麼知道的？
That's how it always is in this place. Whenever I start to speak...
這種情況經常發生，每當我開始說話…
Go on. You might really have him this time.
去吧  你這次可能真的能抓到他
Timur, do you have diarrhea of the mouth or something?
帖木兒，你的嘴是不是拉稀了？
- Welcome, Nükhet. - Thank you.
-歡迎，努赫特  -謝謝
This is for you.
這個給你
- Thank you. - Don't mention it.
-謝謝  -不用謝
- You're so classy. - Not at all.
-你真優雅  -一點都不
I hope I haven't kept you waiting for too long.
我希望我冇有讓你等待太久
I've been waiting for ten years. I live here.
我已經等了十年了  我住在這裏
- We're going out for dinner, right? - Yes.
-我們要出去吃飯了吧？  -是的
We're already there. This is it.
我們已經到了，就在這裏
- This is it? - Yes. After you.
-是嗎  -是的，你先清
What a beautiful building.
多麼美麗的建築
It's a bit rough around the edges, but it's still magnificent.
邊緣有些粗糙，但仍然很宏偉
Abdulhamid the Second built it.
阿蔔杜勒哈米德二世建造了它
He had an Italian architect design it for use by Italian opera singers.
他讓一位義大利建築師為義大利歌劇演員設計了這棟樓
Actually, fun fact.
其實很有趣
This is the first building with an elevator in Istanbul.
這是伊斯坦佈爾的第一座帶有電梯的建築
That's why it keeps breaking.
這就是為什麼電梯總是壞掉
Truly wonderful. Are all the tenants bars like this one?
真的很棒，所有的房客酒吧都像這樣嗎？
No. There's just this one, and a folk bar upstairs.
不，隻有一個，樓上有一個民間酒吧
And a trattoria with divine mezzes. That's where we're going.
還有一家擁有神韻的小餐館，就是我們要去的地方
I live here, of course. But that's it.
我就住在這裏，但僅此而已
Doesn't it get loud at night?
晚上不吵嗎？
It used to.
以前很吵
They used to play the drums at the folk bar. Made quite a ruckus.
他們以前在民謠酒吧打鼓
So I went and had a word with them.
所以我去和他們溝通了一下
We came to terms. They're much quieter now.
我們達成了協議  他們現在安靜得多
You get used to it after a while. They all close after 2 AM.
一段時間後你就習慣了，它們都在淩晨2點後關閉
Only ones left are me and the kids.
隻有我和孩子們
There's no one else in the building.
冇有別人住在這裏了
Truly wonderful. Must be so much fun. So full of life.
真的太棒了，生活如此充實一定很有趣
Agah...
阿加
How about we go in there for a start?
我們過去吧，怎麼樣？
The music's so loud. We won't even hear each other.
音樂省廳很大，我都聽不到你說話
They're playing rock 'n roll!
他們在玩搖滾！
It's been such a long time since I've had some beer in Beyo?lu.
我已經很久冇在貝尤魯喝啤酒了
Let's start there. We can go upstairs later.
讓我們從那裏開始  等下再上樓
Sure. Alright. After you.
當然可以，你先清
They've found whose the DNA from the cat costume belongs to.
他們匹配到了貓服裝的DNA來源
- Is the SWAT team on the way? - Yes.
-特警隊出發了嗎？-是
To you.
敬你
- To you. - To you.
-敬你  -敬你
Life's a beautiful thing, isn't it?
生活真美好，不是嗎？
It is.
是的
- We're almost there. - Tell them to hold until we're there.
-我們快到了  -告訴他們在我們到之前不要行動
Tell the SWAT team not to go in until we're on the scene.
告訴特警隊在我們到現場前不要行動
I have a question.
我有個問題
How did you come up with the idea to write a book named "Life is Traffic"?
你是怎麼想到寫一本名為《生活就是交通》的書的？
- How do you think? - I wouldn't know.
-你怎麼看？  -我不知道
I was in a traffic accident.
我經曆過一次交通事故
I lost my husband in that accident.
我在那次事故中失去了丈夫
I was in the hospital for 11 months.
我在醫院待了11個月
The doctors told me I'd never walk again.
醫生告訴我，我也許不能再走路了
But I met you while doing the tango.
但是我在跳探戈時遇見了你
Indeed...
確實
Everything fell into place after that accident.
事故發生後，一切都井然有序
I realized how simple life is.
我意識到生活多麼簡單
As simple as a traffic accident.
像交通事故一樣簡單
As simple as traffic.
像交通一樣簡單
I love the image of...
我喜歡……
The image of road signs.
道路標誌的圖像
"Stay out." "No u-turns." Stuff like that.
“呆在外麵”  “不要掉頭”這樣的東西
We carry those road signs around with us.
我們隨身攜帶這些路標
Stop. Go. You can park here. You can't park here.
停車  開車  你可以在這裏停車  你不能在這裏停車
The rules for traffic, Agah, turn out to be the rules for life.
交通規則變成了生活規則   阿加
Open up! Police!
開門！警察！
How did the accident happen?
那場意外是怎麼發生的？
- My husband broke a rule. - Which one?
-我丈夫違反了交通規則  -什麼規則？
Fuck!
他媽的！
Sefa, it's me, Firuz!
塞法，是我，菲魯茲！
Tell the team to pull back. I'm opening the door.
告訴特警隊後退  我來開門
Firuz...
菲魯茲
If you want to commit suicide together,
如果你想和某人一起自殺
the first rule is you should ask the other person
第一條規則是你應該先問對方
whether they want to die, as well.
他們是否也想死
Firuz, are you alright?
菲魯茲，你還好嗎？
Did he do it on purpose?
他是故意這樣做的嗎？
The worst part is, I knew what he was when I got married to him.
最糟糕的是，我嫁給他時就知道他是什麼人
I thought I could heal him. But...
我以為可以治愈他
- Whom can you truly heal, right? - Right...
-但又有誰能真正治愈別人呢？  -是的
Firuz...
菲魯茲
Sefa...
塞法
I have a gun pointed at me. Tell the team to pull back.
有槍指著我  讓特警隊後退
Alright.
好的
Lower your weapons. Lower your weapons.
放下武器  放下武器
- What does he want? - I don't know. I'm about to find out.
-兇手想要什麼？-我不知道  我正在問
I'm closing then door now. Alright?
我要關門了  好嗎？
Hold on, Sefa!
等等  塞法！
Pull back. Pull back.
後退  後退
Back!
往後退！
But I have no doubt
但我確信
that people have been healed after reading your book.
讀完你的書後人們就已經康複了
Perhaps...
也許
But I didn't write the book for them.
但是我冇有為別人寫這本書
I wrote the book to heal myself.
我寫這本書是為了治愈自己
If they want to heal themselves, they need to write books of their own.
如果他們想自愈，就需要自己寫書
Speak! Where the fuck did you hide the money? Speak!
說話！你他媽的把錢藏在哪裏？
Speak or you get one in the head! Speak!
說話還是吃槍子！快說！
Did you write any other books?
你還寫其他書嗎？
No...
冇有
I'm still in the investigation part.
我還在構思
- What is it about? - Agah Beyo?lu.
-關於什麼的？-阿加·貝尤魯
What do you mean? Why?
什麼意思？為什麼？
Because something tells me...
因為直覺告訴我……
That nothing is as it seems.
冇有什麼是錶裏如一的
Yes, chief. Alright.
是的，長官
Alright, chief. We're waiting outside.
好的長官  我們在外麵等
Alright, chief. Of course.
好的長官  當然
It's Firuz! Don't shoot, I'm coming out!
我是菲魯茲！別開槍，我要出來！
Excuse me. There was a small problem.
不好意思  我遇到一點小麻煩
I had two bullets jammed in my gun.
我的槍裏有兩發子彈
- Lower your fucking weapons. - I'm glad.
-放下你的武器  -很高興你冇事
I heard you on the radio and came straight over. He fell on me.
我在無線電裏聽到消息直接就過來，但被他擒住了
But I have bad news. He isn't the guy you're looking for.
但是我有個壞消息  他不是你要找的人
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
He was a hired gun.
他是受雇的槍手
He knew there was a serial killer running around in a cat costume.
他知道有一個連環殺手穿著貓服裝到處殺人
He decided to become a cat and catch himself a mouse.
因此他決定成為一隻貓，捉住自己的老鼠
- I'm leaving, then. - Where to?
-我要走了-要去哪裏？
- I'll tell you afterwards. - Alright.
-我待會告訴你-好吧
- You scared us. - Why would you be scared?
-你嚇到我們了  -怎麼會嚇到你？
The devil looks after his own.
魔鬼會照顧自己
I'm here to see Dr. Nedim Do?ru.
我來找內迪姆·多姆醫生
Do you have an appointment?
你有預約嗎？
A moment please.
請稍等
So he hung himself. I knew that's how it would end.
我知道他是上吊自殺的
- Where have you been? - Excuse me?
-你幹嘛去了？  -什麼？
I've been waiting for you for ten years.
我等你十年了
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
I've been waiting for a cop to come asking about Ufuk Terazi.
我一直在等警察來詢問我關於烏福克·泰拉齊的事情
Then...
那麼……
Why didn't you go to the police?
你怎麼不去報警
You wouldn't be asking me that if you knew how this report was made.
如果你知道這份報告是怎麼寫出來的，你就不會問我這個問題了
I had just been assigned to Kambura. To the state hospital there.
我那時剛被分配到坎佈拉的國立醫院
Something horrible had happened. It was before my time.
在我去之前發生了一件可怕的事
A fire. A house had burned down.
發生了一起火災，一棟房子被燒毀了
The family inside had perished.
房子裏麵的人都死了
They brought Ufuk to me. His father did.
他父親把烏福克帶到我這裏
Ufuk didn't want to talk at first.
烏福克一開始不想說話
But when he realized I wasn't a Kamburan, he opened up.
但是當他知道我不是坎佈蘭人時，他開了口
He told the same story over and over again.
他一遍又一遍地講同一個故事
I burned the house down, he said. I didn't believe him at first.
他說：是我把房子燒了  我一開始不相信他
I thought the trauma had altered his perception of reality.
我以為創傷改變了他對現實的看法
But how detailed it all was told me he wasn't hallucinating.
但是他說的那些細節告訴我他並冇有出現幻覺
He wasn't lying, either. So I called the police.
他也冇說謊  所以我找來了警察
I told them what happened, just as I'm telling you now.
我告訴他們發生了什麼事，就像我現在告訴你的那樣
I told them Ufuk confessed.
我告訴他們烏福克認罪了
One day, when I was on night shift, a man came to see me.
有一天，當我夜班時，一個男人來找我
I remember every word he said to me.
我記得他對我說的每句話
"You will forget all about this."
“你會忘記這一切”
"Or you disappear," he said.
“或者你從人間消失，”他說
"What do you mean, disappear?" I asked.
我問“你是什麼意思，消失？”
"You'll disappear the same way people all around this country do."
“你將以這個國家的人們消失的方式消失”
I got what he meant then.
那時候我明白了他的意思
He told me I was to write a report.
他要我寫一份報告
So I did.
所以我就照做了
Who was he?
他是誰？
I don't know.
我不知道
You never asked who he was? What he did?
你從來冇有問過他是誰，他是做什麼的？
Look, Nevra. I'll explain it to you this way...
內芙拉  我這樣跟你說吧……
Conmen prey on hope.
騙子以希望為食
A conman comes to you:
騙子來找你說：
"Give me a dollar and I'll give you ten back."
“給我一塊錢，我會給你十塊錢”
And if you're greedy by nature, you get hopeful and give him the dollar.
如果你天生貪婪，你就會滿懷希望給他錢
But the conmen of this country stopped selling hope.
但是這個國家的騙子們不再販售希望
There's an easier way.
有一個更簡單的方法
People are so afraid of you...
如果人們很怕你……
Tell someone you're a cop on the phone, and they'll give you every dime.
在電話上告訴某人你是警察，他們會把所有錢都給你
If the conmen of a country con you through not hope but fear,
如果一個國家的騙子不是通過希望而是通過恐懼來欺騙你
you never ask them who they are or what they do for a living.
你永遠不會問他們他們是誰，或者問他們以什麼為生
Then...
那麼……
Could you identify him if you saw him?
如果看到他，你能認出他嗎？
Actually...
其實
I was really scared that night.
那天晚上我真的很害怕
I couldn't even look him in the eye.
我甚至不敢看他的眼睛
But you can never tell.
但你永遠不知道
You can never tell what someone might suddenly remember.
你永遠不知道別人會突然想起什麼
- Not even I can. - Give me a second.
-我也不能  -稍等一下
- I don't have to be afraid anymore? - You don't.
-我不必再害怕了？  -不用
- What did he do? - He was a judge.
-他做了什麼？-他生前是法官
Heavy penal court.
重刑法官
After all these years...
這些年來
That's such a load off my back.
那真是我肩上的重擔
Forgetting feels good sometimes. But other times, so does remembering.
有時遺忘感覺很好  但其他時候，還是會想起來
I'll never forget it.
我永遠不會忘記
Where did he come from? Where did he go?
他來自哪裏？去了哪裏？
- Where did that cop come from? - A cop? What cop?
-那警察從哪裏來的？-警察？什麼警察？
The one who took my statement. He spoke to me the next morning.
那個給我做陳述的警察  第二天早上他跟我說了話
Where did he come from?
他來自哪裏？
- The cop? - The cop.
-警察嗎？-是的
Probably from Istanbul. I didn't get his name.
應該是從伊斯坦佈爾來的  我冇記住他的名字
He was young. He was a young man.
他很年輕
I might be able to identify him if I saw a photo.
如果有照片，我也許可以認出他
What is it?
什麼事？
What's that?
那是什麼？
It's what I owe you. It's over. We're even.
這是我欠你的錢  都還清了
I'm done doing your dirty work.
我做完你的髒活了
Is that so?
是這樣嗎？
Tell me it's done.
告訴我結束了
Tell me you're letting me go.
告訴我你會放我走
Suppose I let you go.
假如我讓你走
Will what you've done stop haunting you?
你所做的事會不會不再縈繞在你心頭嗎?
I killed someone over that money!
我為了這些錢殺了人
Oh, Firuz...
哦，菲魯茲
You think you can pay me back in money?
你以為你可以用錢還債嗎
It's a debt in blood.
這是沾血的債務
How's your son doing, by the way?
順便問一下，你兒子好嗎？
In good health, I hope...
我希望他身體健康
The foundation sees to his every need, right?
基金會可以滿足他的所有需求，對嗎？
Let me know if you need anything.
你有任何需要都請告訴我
It's a hard condition.
現在問題很難解決
Not only hard...
不僅難
Also expensive.
還貴
Don't beat yourself up.
不要自責
You're not a bad person.
你不是一個壞人
You're just doing my bidding.
你隻是在執行我的命令
Tell your conscience that the blame's all mine.
告訴你的良心，把責任歸咎於我
It'll feel better.
會好起來的
In the meantime, put these in your pocket.
同時，將它們放回口袋裏
You obviously deserved them.
這顯然是你應得的
Shall we go upstairs? Aren't you getting hungry?
我們可以上樓了嗎？你不餓嗎？
No. This is beautiful.
不，這樣很好
Turn the music off. Turn it off!
關掉音樂！關掉！
- Get out of my way! - What's going on?
-別擋我  -發生了什麼事？
- What? - Get out!
-什麼？-出去！
Get out! Get out!
出去！出去！
- Go! Go! We're closing up! Go on! - What are you doing?
-快走！快走！我們要關門了！出去！-你在做什麼？
Go on, uncle! Out!
走吧  大叔  出去！
- Nükhet! - Go on!
-努赫特！-出去！
- Go on, uncle! Go on! - What do you think you're doing!
-快出去  大叔！快走！-你以為你在做什麼！
- Get back, bitch! - Throw them out! Throw them out!
-回來，臭婊子！-把他們趕出去！快把他們趕出去！
Go on, what are you looking at?
快走，你愁啥？
Get the fuck out of here!
滾蛋！
- They didn't pay their tax this month! - Fuck you!
-他們這個月冇有交稅！-去尼瑪的！
Do you have a death wish or something?
你有什麼遺願嗎？
That's exactly what I have. What will you do about it?
我還真有，你能怎樣？
- Somebody help him! - Shut him up!
-快來人幫幫他  -閉嘴
Nükhet, I'm so sorry. I really am.
努赫特，我真的很抱歉
This kind of thing never happens around here.
這種事情從來冇有在這裏發生過
Don't worry about it. It's not your fault.
不用擔心  這不是你的錯
It can't be helped. Besides, I had so much fun.
冇辦法  除此之外  我玩得很開心
I'm mad that I didn't say anything to those two-bit crooks.
我很生氣，我冇對那些混蛋說些什麼
Don't be silly. What if they have guns? How do we know they don't?
別傻了，如果他們有槍怎麼辦？我們怎麼知道有冇有槍？
Isn't it that way in traffic also? You should never pick a fight.
交通規則不也是這樣嗎？永遠都不要打架
You don't know who anyone might be. What if they have a gun in their car?
你不知道他們是什麼人  如果他們的車上有槍怎麼辦？
What we did was right, not getting involved in their affairs.
我們做的是對的，冇有參與他們的事情
Thank you so much for everything. Good night.
謝謝你所做的一切  晚安
Good night...
晚安
- Some outfit. What's this now? - He looks ridiculous.
-這人穿的什麼衣服？-他看起來很荒謬
Are you from the mafia?
你們是黑手黨的人嗎？
Hush. It's saying something.
噓，他說了些什麼
- What? - I asked you if you're from the mafia.
-什麼？ -我問你們是否來自黑手黨
- He's a loon. - Are you drunk or something?
-他是個瘋子  -你喝醉了還是怎樣？
Are you looking for trouble?
你在找麻煩嗎？
Hold on. Show me your face. Show it!
等等，讓我看看你的臉！
Come on, we have another stop to make at S?tk?'s.
算了，我們還要去下個地方
Fucking clown.
該死的小醜
I asked you if you're from the mafia, my boy.
我問你們是否來自黑手黨
Yes. That's exactly what we are. So what?
是的，那正是我們的身份，那又如何呢？
Here's the mafia for you.
這就是做黑手黨的下場
Just a bunch of wannabes.
隻是一群小混混罷了
PERSONAL
個人